okay
doing a little bit more research for the
bashar
sta um an interesting paper i found
is by e richards called the earth power
spectrum and its potential as a usable
energy source you can find it
uh just google search for it um but this
paper talks about
uh different frequencies uh explored by
different inventors over over time
tesla was kind of in the 40 40 kilohertz
to 200 kilohertz range
this is 100 years ago hubbard had these
feet uh wires four of them each of the
compass directions this is sort of
around uh
if you think of 1200 feet as a quarter
wave this is around 200 kilohertz
hands uh kohler was around 180 kilohertz
stando in a book called the cosmic
conspiracy
in chapter four mentions uh 14.3
kilohertz as being important
so the the conclusion is we want to make
a device that can sort of um
pick up the energy in the 14.3
to 250 kilohertz range this is where
lightning strikes happen
this is where uh solar events like solar
flares and other
solar events impact the earth and induce
a lot of energy in our
in our magnetic field and ionosphere and
so forth so
this is the range of frequencies we want
to be in
so this conclusion is uh making me um
consider going to a full-scale sta um
because what we're after is a larger
inductance so that we can get down to
those lower frequencies
we want low resistance
because um we want it to resonate longer
each time it receives a ping
from the environment and that translates
to larger gauge wire
um and we want to do this at room
temperature we're not using
anything esoteric like super
conductivity
we want it to be an air coil so
achieving
large inductance means that it has to be
physically large
because we're not putting any
ferromagnetic material in the core
now bashar has a requirement that it fit
under a three foot
tetrahedron three feet in height that's
91.4 centimeters for you metric people
and i find it amusing that this
requirement
is given uh in the sense of being a trig
problem rather than just giving us the
dimensions straight out so
assuming i did the math correctly um the
diameter i come
up with is 14.37 inches 36.5 centimeters
the height is 24.26 inches 61.6
centimeters
the tetrahedron is 36 inches 91.4
the side is 44 inches 111.8
centimeters so the height height of the
cone is um
14.37 that's greater than a foot
i'm sorry the height is 24.26 inches
greater than two feet
and the diameter is 14.37 inches
hi so um in kind of a richard dreyfus
mashed potato mountain moment this
weekend
i built this thing it took me about
a day and a half to almost two days
most of the time wiring so you can see
that this
basher sta is quite large my room is
kind of small so i can't back up
too well um i have two coils
yin and yang the black one
is the full cone shaped
uh coil and the white one
is cut in half and then there's the
other section
in here uh with a wire that pokes
through
to to establish the connection from the
outer white one to the inner white one
um my table top is about 33 inches
above the ground the coil
um is right up to my chin
i'm about five foot ten so this thing is
gigantic so let me uh go over some
notes on the construction technique
some of the parts you would need if you
want to replicate this
you would need 4 22 by eight a 22
inch by 28 poster boards um
two of them are taped together so that
you can cut a very large
uh 102 degree
uh cone cone-shaped template
when you tape this together uh it's kind
of flimsy
but when you as you wrap the wire around
it
the cone snaps into a more rigid form
so what i recommend is you stuff uh
clothing like a
material and shirts and pants and things
into it to make it rigid while you're
putting the wire on
then you can take that stuff out because
the wire will hold it rigid
um i used shipping tape i used scotch
tape i decided to just
make my life easy and just scotch tape
each wire loop as i went around
so there's eight pieces of tape each
each loop so it's quite a bit of taping
but
um this was the easiest way to connect
it now
um now people don't usually usually use
scotch tape
when they're making uh coils for uh
radio but this is such a large
inductance
coil that the capacitance from from the
tape is
nec is negligible uh you might need some
clip leads
uh it's a convenient way to make the
connections of the wires you could
solder them onto the wires of the
coil and here's the expensive part
i used two 500 foot spools
of 14 gauge wire
and it cost me about 100 bucks usd
so um so much for being a free energy
device
it's expensive you can buy a solar panel
like a 15 watt solar panel for less than
that and
be done with be done with it but you
know this is science so let's just
you know experiment here some of the
tools you might need are
a 36 inch yardstick which is useful
a protractor to measure this 102 degree
thing
scissors wire cutters um i use uh two
lazy susans one to hold the spool
and one to put the uh the cone-shaped
coil on
and uh if you're careful to
uh make the wire go onto the cone with
the same
uh turn angle that the
spool has then you don't have to bend
the wire each time
makes life much easier you might need a
knife
so two lazy susans you might want to get
really big
diameter lazy susan's ones to match the
diameter of the
coil i noticed some ham radio website
picked up some of the videos i've been
making on this bachelor sta
and that's great i'm hoping some of the
hobbyists that know all about radio
will attempt to replicate this because
not only
might this thing be a useful uh
antenna for ulf and
long wave reception
uh you know it's basically an antenna
research project
beyond just the free energy
experimentation
um so here's some specs that i use i
used a wire gauge of 14
awg that's an american gauge
for you people in europe you're looking
for a wire that has a diameter of about
1.628 millimeters
and 8.236
ohms per kilometer so we're looking for
basically low resistance
wire and you can even go thicker here
some people are using copper tubing
and going really thick and that might
mean that you
would change the geometry to be even
bigger
the number of turns that i wrapped was
approximately 180 per
coil the black coil actually ended up
with more
i made a mistake when i bought the two
spools of wire uh the black wire is
actually
solid copper rigid highly bendable
the white coil has stranded
copper wire same gauge but two different
styles of wire
and i found that the stranded wire was
really easy to put onto the paper form
so i would recommend stranded wire
however the solid copper wire
offers a benefit of being a little bit
more massive maybe
very rigid the cone the cone is held
very rigidly
onto it it makes a much more solid
structure this one's more flimsy
so that happy mistake allowed me to sort
of see the differences between those two
types of wires but if you want to make
your life easy
go for the stranded wire the calculated
index i found a formula for cone-shaped
coils
and calculated these dimensions in and i
ended up with a number
approximately 1.8 millihenries
i have a very crude way of measuring
inductance using a kit that i bought
and i don't know how reliable it is but
i was getting a number
a measured inductance after i made these
coils
of somewhere between 2.4 and 2.9
millihenries
which might point to the fact that the
formula for a cone-shaped coil uh
breaks down after you get to a certain
size and maybe
uh and this is not with the coils
arranged penetrating this just coils by
themselves as
a separate cone shaped coil the the
inductance was measured like this so
maybe the met the formula for a
cone-shaped coil
changes as the cone gets larger
which is fascinating maybe the
inductance is larger than you think it
is
the resistance in the wire that i
measured
turned out to be uh 1.1 ohms or maybe a
little bit less because
i had to add a clip lead and and
the long leads from the from the ohm
meter um
so using using the uh the wire gauge
ohmage
number that translates about 436 feet of
wire i don't think i used that much wire
i think
i probably used around 370
feet of wire per per cone
an individual on youtube point pointed
me to the work of walter and lau
russell they also were playing with
cone-shaped
coils and got some results you might
investigate them
i don't know too much about walter
russell and his work
but he does seem to have an interesting
periodic table that he invented
then another person at energetic forum
pointed at
pointed us to the crossfield antenna
which is
another thing that people are
experimenting with which is an inverted
cone shaped coil antenna
very very large but 1 50th
the size of the wavelength so
some radio folks are really interested
in this antenna and whether or not it
performs
um
foreign
you